JOHN HOYSA

Austin, Texas 78729 • 512.914.0955 • john.hoysa@gmail.com • johnhoysa.com

Front-End Developer

Highly versatile front-end developer with extensive experience in HTML, CSS, Content Management Systems and E-Commerce environments. Intermediate knowledge of JavaScript and jQuery. Excellent collaborative and interpersonal skills; able to establish lasting relationships with clients, designers, and developers. Easy to adapt and excel with deadline-driven projects and work well with creative teams or independently.

Skills and Tools

HTML, CSS, SASS, JavaScript, Web Vitals, Craft CMS, ExpressionEngine, WordPress, GIT, NPM, Twig, JIRA and Confluence, Sketch, Adobe CS, and MS Office. Fluent on Mac or PC platforms.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

MACSALES.COM / OWC DIGITAL - Austin, Texas

HTML / CSS Developer, 2015 to Present

Collaborate with a team of front and back-end developers to create, maintain, and update all websites within the company umbrella. Work closely with stakeholders and marketing leads to build and migrate content into a CMS for manageability in an e-Commerce environment. Help oversee and train others on how to use and manage the CMS. Work in tandem with UI/UX lead for creative implementation and execution. Actively participate in A/B testing, advise on insights and revise as necessary.

- Develop and integrate new e-commerce platform and marketing pages to Craft CMS, manage page and content creation of macsales.com.
- Creation and maintenance of main product website, owcdigital.com
- Produce coding style guide and documentation that describe the current build process and various parts
 of CMS work within the control panel and web templates.
- Help ensure that desktop layouts will translate easily to mobile views.

John Hoysa - Austin, Texas

Dev Consultant, 2005 to Present

Numerous projects created for diverse clients, including Lamberts BBQ, Codesign Austin, Tom Hurt, and Hamilton & Associates, working closely with Foda Studio, a brand consultancy and design agency. Analyzed market trends, graphic design / web development tendencies, and specifications. Migrated data from old static sites to new CMS powered sites.

- Improve website usability and business results by revamping customer's sites to highlight products and services; increased interest and loyalty in brands, providing suggestions for design updates.
- Devise and implement effective SEO strategies that enhance web design and responsiveness to attract audiences.

EDUCATIONAL SERVICE CENTER REGION 13 - Austin, Texas

Web Developer & Project Lead, 2012 to 2015

Directed web development project life cycle, from defining goals / needs and providing technical insights to testing and delivery; adhered to client's requirements, including budget restraint and project scope. Designed applications with Bootstrap framework, ExpressionEngine, and Craft CMS, focusing on delivering flexible,

customize, and user-centric web pages; maintained communications with owners to facilitate management of sites and content, allowing clients to have more control over content.

- Trained users on WordPress platform, publishing tools, and site maintenance; instructed about how to
 update and maintain their page at esc13.net, empowering creation of educational and interesting content.
- Developed comprehensive training materials for teachers and school administrators using jQuery, Flash, and interactive PDF.
- Generated wireframes, prototypes, graphics, and user experience while completing complex coding with the use of web programming languages, such as HTML / CSS, Flash, and jQuery.

NETSPEND | KINNSER SOFTWARE – Austin & Rollingwood, Texas Designer & Front-End Developer, 2009 to 2010

Identified client's needs and goals to develop corporate and customer sites. Carried out A/B Testing in collaboration with NetSpend's team to analyze email campaigns and print collateral performance. Suggested design changes and enhancements as necessary to optimize website usability. Boosted Kinnser's web traffic by rewriting and testing its webpage.

- Improved web traffic by conceptualizing and launching user-friendly sites, determining layouts, color schemes, graphics, and visuals according to brand guidelines.
- Built the front-end to Kinnser's web application in collaboration with ColdFusion developers to new features that increase functionality.

CTA ARCHITECTS ENGINEERS | INNOVATIVE AFTERMARKET SYSTEMS – Austin, Texas Web Designer & Multimedia Designer, 2003 to 2008

Continued development of CTA Architects Engineer's CMS, allowing management and maintenance of web page and its content. Created, edited, and published texts and images for website while adhering to company's requirements. Utilized numerous tools and languages to generate engaging presentations, design brand, and icons for Innovative Aftermarket Systems.

• Collaborated in InnovativeAfter Market's marketing and promotional efforts by ensuring brand consistency and distribution of eye-catching interactive and informative print collateral.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Fine Arts with a Specialization in Photography Southwest Texas State University, San Marcos, Texas

Photography & Arts Program

Rochester Institute of Technology - College of Art and Design, Rochester, New York